Nnamdi Daniel Aghanya

9 Herewood Green, Stewartby, Bedford, MK43 9SZ daniel2468114@gmail.com, aghanyan@uni.coventry.ac.uk • +44 (0)7417 428261 • github.com/emocreator

Profile

Nnamdi is currently a student of Coventry University studying Computer Hardware and Software Engineering (BEng) and Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) studying Statistics and Data Science (MicroMasters Program). He holds a Python Data Analyst, Python Data Scientist, and Python Programmer certification from DataCamp and Google Data Analyst Certification from Coursera, among others. He has worked with a variety of schools' projects data types and have experience in data gathering, arranging, translating, and disseminating it. He also has experience in the full project life cycle from design/ask to implementation/act. He is an active presenter and a good communicator with the ability to disseminate information in a simple, reliable, and beneficial manner to end-users and stakeholders. He is innovative in problem-solving and assessing changes for the best use of organizational resources. Further, he is team player with leadership and analytical skills and comfortable working in an environment associated with Agile frameworks, working collaboratively or autonomously and has great understanding of complex algorithms.

Education

Coventry University - Coventry, The United Kingdom

Expected Graduation: June 2024

Computer Hardware and Software Engineering BEng (Hons, 3.9/4.0 GPA)

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Analogue Circuits and Embedded Systems, Analogue and Digital Electronics, Linear Algebra, Cyber Security.

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) - Online

Expected Graduation: June 2023

Micro Master's Program in Statistics and Data Science(3.5/4.0 GPA)

Relevant Coursework: Machine learning with python-from linear models to deep learning,

Knowledge/Skills

- Big Data & Machine Learning: Python (e.g., Scikit-learn, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib)
- Lab operation of electronics testing equipment including oscilloscopes, function generators, and logic analyzers
- Programming in Python, R, Java, C, C++, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, React, TypeScript, JavaScript.
- Data Science & Miscellaneous Technologies: Tableau, Microsoft Excel, Data science pipeline SQL, Google BigQuery skills (cleansing, wrangling, visualization, modelling, interpretation), Experimental design, OOP, OOD, APIs, Git.
- Linux

Certification

DataCamp – Online May 2021

- Python Data Analyst
- Python Data Scientist

The Odin Project – Online Expected Graduation: May 2022

A self-learning Web development training and certification

JPMorgan Chase Software Engineering Virtual Experience – Online Dec 2021

Software engineering training and certification

Google Data Analyst Certification – Online

Dec 2021

Software engineering training and certification

Work Experience

Machine Learning Junior Project manager – RD Land – Remote (Part time)

Dec 2021 - To date

Part of the machine learning team tasked with the creation and research of portable and marketable artificial intelligent partners and friends.

- Developed a self-learning Utility Discord chatbot for simulating message interactions between two individuals.
 - ✓ Derives data by scrapping the user's past messages using the discord API, feeding the data back into the bot to be used to simulate a certain individual speech pattern, using react.js.
 - ✓ Stores Admins logs and settings using MongoDB as a database
 - ✓ Uses Gpt-2 model to predict both the question-and-answer pairings by passing the question and passing semantically similar answers present in the dataset apart from the answer itself, useful when simulating how an individual reacts.
- Engineered and Deployed Front End UX infrastructure for the company for Amazon Web Services cloud
- Creating new features using Machine Learning, Three.js, A-frame & JavaScript.
- Lead a team to meet deadlines and produce optimized, high-quality environments and user interfaces for head-mounted displays (VR) and PC.
- Work closely with the development team towards enhancement and implementation of product roadmap to realize the creative vision.

Adecco Mar 2021 – Aug 2021

Warehouse Associate – team leader

- Offered friendly and efficient service to all customers
- Complied with organization policies and laws regarding sorting and delivering packages.
- Unloading delivery vehicles with fork lift truck
- Making sure all stock are labelled and stored correctly
- Mentoring new staff members, providing full training in safe handling and corporate health and safety procedures
- Ensure compliance with health and safety policy of the warehouse
- Ensure that orders are shipped to customers on time and without damage.

Shekinah Information security consultancy LTD, Bangor, WA

Jun 2019 – Jul 2019

Information Security Consultant Intern

- Collaborated with the team in creating algorithms to check the strength of client security measures.
- Responsible for creating algorithm that determines the strength of the security that protects both employers and customers' data.
- Act as a resource for other office staff members.
- Assist in updating technical and end user documentation
- Work on project planning through collaboration
- Assist in facilitating meetings and/or discussions
- Presenting showcasing results.

Interests

Playing video games, watching movies and enjoying timeout with friends

Referees

To be provided on request.